export const FOODANDNUTRITIONA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. During cake preparation, the tool used for scrapping edge of the the bowl when creaming is a",
A: "spatula",
B: "fork",
C: "butter knife",
D: "table spoon",
answer: "A. spatula",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The law that would protect a consumer injured by a faulty food processor is the",
A: "food safety act",
B: "consumer protection act",
C: "consumer right act",
D: "environmental health act",
answer: "B. consumer protection act",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Animal proteins are termed first class proteins because they are",
A: "are easily digested and absorbed in the body",
B: "are easily utilized by the body",
C: "contains all essential amino acids",
D: "contain essential and non-essential amino acids",
answer: "C. contains all essential amino acids",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. In kitchen, the storage, washing up and food preparation areas form the",
A: "work centre",
B: "work triangle",
C: "island",
D: "layout",
answer: "A. work centre",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Encouraging teenagers to develop recipes from leftovers help to improve culinary skills and",
A: "time management",
B: "food habits",
C: "energy management",
D: "creative ability",
answer: "D. creative ability",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. After digestion, nutrients pass through the walls of the",
A: "small intestines to the blood stream",
B: "stomach to the veins",
C: "large intestines to the blood stream",
D: "stomach to the liver",
answer: "A. small intestines to the blood stream",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Substances that prevent the effective utilization of nutrients in the body are called",
A: "anti-oxidants",
B: "phytonutrients",
C: "phycotoxins",
D: "anti-nutrients",
answer: "D. anti-nutrients",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A meal of fried chicken, braised rice and sweet pancakes is high in",
A: "energy",
B: "protein",
C: "fibre",
D: "vitamins",
answer: "A. energy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The kitchen tool in the diagram above is used for",
A: "Mixing dough",
B: "Creaming fat",
C: "Beating egg",
D: "Rubbing-in fat",
answer: "C. Beating egg",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The sticky substance obtained from heating sugar solution is known as",
A: "syrup",
B: "treacle",
C: "caramel",
D: "glaze",
answer: "C. caramel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Skewers are used to  \nI. test doneness of cake.  \nII. string kebabs.  \nIll. truss poultry",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "I, II and III",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "D. II and III only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Planning the purchase of food items with a portion of the family income is termed",
A: "shopping",
B: "budgeting",
C: "expenditure",
D: "spending",
answer: "B. budgeting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following table appointment is a flatware?",
A: "cutlery",
B: "crockery",
C: "A Centre piece",
D: "Table linen",
answer: "A. cutlery",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A mother who just had a baby is preparing for the naming ceremony. What is the first step in organizing the party?",
A: "Buying the ingredients",
B: "Preparing the shopping list",
C: "Sending out invitations",
D: "Welcoming the guests",
answer: "B. Preparing the shopping list",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The main reason for using leftover rice to prepare rice pudding is to",
A: "cut cost",
B: "change the texture",
C: "improve flavour",
D: "improve appearance",
answer: "A. cut cost",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. An example of a moist method of cooking is",
A: "steaming",
B: "baking",
C: "grilling",
D: "roasting",
answer: "A. steaming",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A consumer bought a refrigerator and on getting home he/she discovered it was not cooling well. In order to claim warranty on the refrigerator the consumer should",
A: "present the invoice",
B: "return the refrigerator",
C: "complain in the media",
D: "present the receipt",
answer: "D. present the receipt",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. If a home maker always feed her children with canned fish and conflates, the disadvantage of the foods is that they",
A: "reduce cooking time",
B: "are not readily available",
C: "lack some nutrients",
D: "require more cooking time",
answer: "C. lack some nutrients",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In the preparation of fruit drinks, citrus peels are boiled in the syrup in order to",
A: "extract flavour",
B: "give it a bitter-sweet taste",
C: "improve its nutrient content.",
D: "improve colour",
answer: "A. extract flavour",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A bakery got a contract to prepare ginger bread. What is the appropriate raising agent for the bread?",
A: "Baking powder",
B: "Yeast",
C: "Bicarbonate of soda",
D: "Steam",
answer: "B. Yeast",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. An important factor that aids the process of deterioration in meat is the presence of salt",
A: "preservative",
B: "moisture",
C: "additive",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "B. moisture",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The general name for the internal organs of cattle that are used as food is",
A: "entrails",
B: "giblets",
C: "roes",
D: "offals",
answer: "D. offals",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The method of cooking illustrated in the diagram is",
A: "boiling",
B: "steaming",
C: "poachin",
D: "braising",
answer: "C. poaching",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The method of cooking is most suitable for",
A: "yam",
B: "egg",
C: "cabbage",
D: "plantain",
answer: "C. cabbage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The mode of heat transfer within the equipment",
A: "is radiation",
B: "is conduction",
C: "are convection and conduction",
D: "are convection radiation.",
answer: "C. are convection and conduction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following celebrations is observed as a national holiday?",
A: "Wedding anniversaries odours.",
B: "Religious festivals",
C: "Graduation ceremonies",
D: "Napting ceremonies",
answer: "B. Religious festivals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. An example of root vegetable is",
A: "carrot",
B: "onion",
C: "leek",
D: "cabbage",
answer: "A. carrot",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. An example of a leavener",
A: "egg",
B: "steam",
C: "water",
D: "wine",
answer: "B. steam",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Reduction of water content of fish to create an unfavourable environment for enzyme action is",
A: "sterilization",
B: "pasteuration",
C: "dehydration",
D: "homogenizatio",
answer: "C. dehydration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The three classes of fish are",
A: "white, oily and shell fish",
B: "white, molluscs and dry fish",
C: "crustaceans, molluscs and white fish",
D: "lean, oily and white fish",
answer: "A. white, oily and shell fish",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The porosity of egg shell is important for",
A: "gaseous exchange",
B: "separation of water and fat",
C: "separation of yolk and albumen",
D: "increased shell",
answer: "A. gaseous exchange",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Ventilation is needed in the kitchen mainly to",
A: "provide illimitation",
B: "remove heat and cooking odours",
C: "ensure safety",
D: "prevent eye strain and accidents",
answer: "B. remove heat and cooking odours",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A kitchen ware with a special finish suitable for use in an oven is",
A: "glass",
B: "pyrex",
C: "teflon",
D: "enamel",
answer: "B. pyrex",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. During freezing, bacteria action in food is",
A: "inhibited",
B: "destroyed",
C: "activated",
D: "maintained",
answer: "A. inhibited",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following groups are classes of vegetables?  \nI. Green leafy vegetables  \nII. Variegated vegetables  \nIII. Legumes and pulses  \nIV. Roots and tubers",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and IV onl",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "D. I, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The difference between rough puff and flaky pastry is the",
A: "method of incorporating fat",
B: "quantity of fat used",
C: "addition of raining agent",
D: "temperature of water used",
answer: "A. method of incorporating fat",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. A suitable floor for a modern kitchen should be made from responsible materials that are",
A: "washable and non-absorbent",
B: "washable and porous",
C: "porous and polished",
D: "absorbent and polished",
answer: "A. washable and non-absorbent",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Heavy weight and even distribution of heat are characteristics of a cookware made from",
A: "aluminium",
B: "ceramic",
C: "iron",
D: "glass",
answer: "C. iron",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. One of the best sources of protein for a vegetarian is",
A: "soy beans",
B: "lentils",
C: "groundnuts",
D: "melon seeds",
answer: "A. soy beans",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. the nutrient deficiency illustrated above results from lack of vitamin",
A: "B",
B: "D",
C: "E",
D: "K",
answer: "B. D",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The deficient nutrient is responsible for the absorption of",
A: "iron",
B: "potassium",
C: "iodin",
D: "calcium",
answer: "D. calcium",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The food sources of the deficient nutrient include",
A: "oily fish and egg",
B: "brown rice and oat",
C: "lean meat and nuts",
D: "whole wheat and sausage",
answer: "A. oily fish and egg",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Sour milk is desirable in the preparation of",
A: "currant bread",
B: "tarts",
C: "scones",
D: "ginger bread",
answer: "D. ginger bread",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. One of the consequences of food taboo is",
A: "hunger",
B: "malnutrition",
C: "obesity",
D: "epidemy",
answer: "B. malnutrition",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The main reason for wrapping food before storing in a refrigerator is to",
A: "prevent loss of moisture",
B: "maintain shape",
C: "prolong shelf life",
D: "prevent discolouration",
answer: "A. prevent loss of moisture",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A dish that can be made from leftover sponge cake is",
A: "parkings",
B: "cabinet pudding",
C: "queen of pudding",
D: "trifle",
answer: "D. trifle",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The preparation of syrup for fruit drinks, the proportion of sugar to water is",
A: "50g:500ml.",
B: "100g:500ml",
C: "150g:500ml.",
D: "200g:500ml",
answer: "B. 100g:500ml",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. In bread making, the action of yeast is retarded if too",
A: "little sugar is added",
B: "much salt is added",
C: "little fat is added",
D: "much water is added",
answer: "B. much salt is added",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. In yeast, the enzyme that converts glucose to carbon dioxide and alcohol is",
A: "maltose",
B: "diastase",
C: "zymase",
D: "invertase",
answer: "C. zymase",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. It is best to buy food items in bulk when they are",
A: "fresh",
B: "expensive",
C: "plentiful",
D: "scarce",
answer: "C. plentiful",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. An organization arranged a get together for its staff at XYZ hotel by pm. This type of gathering is called",
A: "conference",
B: "luncheon",
C: "picnic",
D: "buffet",
answer: "B. luncheon",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. In place setting, the napkin is placed",
A: "on the side plate",
B: "beside the fork",
C: "at the tip of the knife",
D: "beside the water glass",
answer: "B. beside the fork",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. Which of the following statements is true about réchauffé dishes?",
A: "Fresh ingredients are not required",
B: "Additional oil is needed",
C: "Foods are reheated",
D: "Dried ingredients must be adde",
answer: "C. Foods are reheated",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. A suitable meal substitute in diets is",
A: "groundnuts",
B: "tofu",
C: "bean balls",
D: "locust beans",
answer: "C. bean balls",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. The success of an organization depends on employees’",
A: "demand for more income",
B: "respect for organizational values",
C: "attainment of managerial positions",
D: "respect for management",
answer: "B. respect for organizational values",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. The major role of vitamin E in the body is to",
A: "help in bone formation",
B: "aid blood clotting",
C: "act as an anti-oxidant",
D: "enhance protein metabolism",
answer: "C. act as an anti-oxidant",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. An appropriate snack for an obese person is",
A: "meat turn overs and milk shake",
B: "sausage rolls and orange drink",
C: "queen cakes and carbonated",
D: "sponge cake and lemonade",
answer: "C. queen cakes and carbonated",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. The most important factor to consider when planning meals is the",
A: "foods in season",
B: "cooking method",
C: "food value",
D: "service skill",
answer: "C. food value",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. To entertain guests appropriately, a good hostess should  \nI. be pleasant and thoughtful  \nII. partake in conversation at the table  \nIII. be considerate of people’s feelings  \nIV. be up-to-date with current affairs.",
A: "I, II and III only",
B: "I, II and IV onl",
C: "II and III only",
D: "II and IV only",
answer: "A. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]